#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

### Summary

Seek the Position of Business Analyst Remarkably gifted, knowledgeable and resourceful Business Analyst with over four years experience in collecting and analyzing data to evaluate existing and potential product and service markets; identifying and monitoring competitors and researching market conditions and changes in the industry that may affect sales. Exceptional ability to respond to information requests from management, posts and other key stakeholders as appropriate. Profound ability to effectively manage individual performance in accordance with the management system. Great ability to plan, develop and implement research projects. Remarkable ability to understand research principles and analysis. Proven ability to analyze complex data and communicate and disseminate this information to laypeople clearly and accurately. In-depth ability to talk knowledgeably about implications in context. Strong ability to give attention to detail and to prioritize tasks and meet deadlines. Uncommon ability to manage the demands of personal work peaks and demands, and manage time effectively. Strong project management experience. Strong team management skill and immense ability to form and manage relationships. Excellent verbal and written communication skills. Profound interpersonal skills and the ability to communicate with people across the organization, and externally. Remarkable project management and strategic planning skills. Multi Lingual capabilities to communicate with International customers and stakeholders. Great level of computer literacy and advanced knowledge of Microsoft applications, including Word, Excel, Access and Powerpoint.

- Strong communication skills
- Creative
- Focused
- Poised
- Charismatic
- Collaborative
- Incorporates feedback quickly
- Team player
- Flexible schedule

## Accomplishments

Completed [Number] years of acting classes with [Celebrity Acting Coach] . Portrayed [Role] in the mini-series "[Mini-Series Title]" in [Year] . Received Best Actor Award in [Month, year] from [Organization name] .

Experience

01/2008 to Current

Business Analyst Morgan Stanley i1/4 IN

- Develop marketing plans and strategies for the department; formulate long range plans for marketing activities; create strategies for the
  introduction of new goods and services and the expansion of existing services; participate in overall departmental strategic planning and
  management activities.
- Plan, develop, coordinate and participate in various marketing research activities to identify customer preferences and attitudes and to enhance products and services.
- Conduct market research to determine customer needs and impressions of department goods and services; design survey instruments and
  coordinate the collection of data; compile information, analyze results and prepare reports setting forth customer attitudes and trends and
  appropriate marketing recommendations and conclusions.
- Maintain relationship with representatives of the media to place articles in local, regional and national newspapers and magazines; provide photographs to the news media.
- Design advertisements; prepare press releases and articles; develop, write, edit and lay out departmental publications; coordinate with printers and other personnel to ensure publications are printed on schedule and according to budgetary and other requirements.
- Plan and organize various departmental activities and public relations events to promote goods and services; prepare and deliver presentations to promote the goals of the department.
- Determine fiscal requirements and prepare budgetary recommendations; formulate and manage the annual marketing and advertising budgets.
- Performed cost and time estimates, proposal development, budgetary planning, manpower planning, performance reviews, and
  salary/contract administration Facilitate interviews and meetings with the various stakeholders to gather business requirements Supervise
  market research interns, students and other marketing support positions in conducting and tabulating surveys, as well as in the areas of
  design, graphic arts, photography and the use of desktop publishing computer software; supervise the design and production of marketing
  and communications materials, including advertisements, flyers and posters to ensure proper focus, quality and content.
- Perform other related duties incidental to the work described herein.

### 01/2007 to 01/2008

Business Analyst Morgan Stanley

- Conducted research and analysis to identify the business problem.
- Modeled current business environment and produced cost effective redevelopment options for the system to capture property project details.
- Created detailed workflow diagrams of existing and of the proposed system.
- Created and maintained all related procedural documentation.
- Worked closely with the development team to clarify and ensure adherence to business requirements.
- Reporting and presentation of key components and milestones to Top Management.
- Collected and analyzed data on customer demographics, preferences, needs, and buying habits to identify potential markets and factors affecting product demand.
- Prepared reports of findings, illustrating data graphically and translating complex findings into written text.

- Measured and assessed customer and employee satisfaction.
- Forecasted and tracked marketing and sales trends, analyzing collected data.
- Measured the effectiveness of marketing, advertising, and communications programs and strategies.
- Gathered data on competitors and analyzed their prices, sales, and method of marketing and distribution.
- Monitored industry statistics and followed trends in trade literature.

# 01/2005 to 01/2007

Business Analyst Morgan Stanley i1/4 CA

- Involved in the design and development of the "Hastey Hastey".
- Documented information such as project status, reports, memos and project specifications.
- Obtained the initial requirements from the client and furnished those details to the development team.
- Gathered user/business requirements, generated business models and performed use case analysis.
- Conducted individual and group sessions with business, production and technical units.
- Implemented a structured system development methodology with emphasis on Rational Unified Process, which dramatically improved productivity and reduced errors.
- Suggested enhancements to the website Prepare business process flow diagrams and perform use case analysis.
- Assist in Effort Estimation, Planning, task Scheduling, Tracking and Requirements Management.
- Develop timelines for project delivery, and assist manage projects and resources to successful completion.
- Accountable for interaction and communication with all levels of management, project management office and all team members involved
  with assigned projects to ensure timely and adequate testing resource allocation during testing phases Assist the project manager in risk
  analysis, of the application to identify the key risks involved in the project and also in effort estimation and task scheduling.

### Education

2009

Bachelor's Degree: Business Administration Management and Marketing Georgian Court University i'/4 State GPA: Distinction and 2006 Deans Honors List Business Administration Management and Marketing Distinction and 2006 Deans Honors List Research Publications \*Implementation of organizational behavior in work environment \*Business and finance analysis structure of organizations Skills

advertisements, advertising, budgets, business process, clarify, content, contract administration, client, delivery, desktop publishing, documentation, edit, finance, focus, forth, graphic arts, Develop marketing plans, market research, marketing research, marketing, marketing and communications, marketing and sales, materials, meetings, office, newspapers, organizational, performance reviews, personnel, photography, posters, presentations, press releases, printers, project management, proposal development, public relations, Publications, quality, Reporting, Research, risk analysis, Rational Unified Process, sales, Scheduling, statistics, strategic planning and management, structured, surveys, translating, website, workflow, written, articles